本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：sienna  某羽  包包  幸田实果子  吃货丁小七
翻译：卫老哥  feilixiaozi  姚小事儿  MythCreator  cs小明漫画家
翻译：面条打包子  小花豆  guzppi  七个柚子酱  木浅薰
翻译：王小麦  时间轴：包包  凭陵新月  贝贝  阿丹
校对：卫老哥  某羽  王小麦
后期：8T  MythCreator  总监：王小麦
真探
前情提要
而是我们有事没做完
We left something undone.
我们必须做完
We got to fix it.
那是我们在伊拉斯查的案子
You and I were on the case in Erath.
有个女孩说她被一个长着绿耳朵的意面怪
Girl comes forward and says she was chased through the woods
追进了树林
by a spaghetti monster with green ears.
我觉得那就是脸上有伤疤的那个男人
Now, I think that this is our man with the scars on his face.
比利·李·塔特尔怎么了
What happened to Billy Lee Tuttle?
我观察了他的房子好几周
I staked his places out for weeks.
在那里的保险箱里找到了那些
Found those in the safe there.
有一卷录像带
There's a videotape.
不
No!
在所有这些东奔西跑的孩子们中
Out of all these kids running around
有没有个孩子
you remember one that maybe had
脸下边可能有道疤
scars all across the bottom of his face?
那是山姆先生的孙子吧
I think that was Mr. Sam's grandchild.
能帮我确认件事吗  一件事
Could you have a look at something for me? ne thing.
你知道卡寇莎
You know Carcosa?
我又调查了下玛丽·方特诺特
Did some backtracking on the Marie Fontenot stuff.
治安官并没有投诉她
Sheriff didn't take the original complaint,
是代理治安官做得
deputy did.
史蒂夫·杰瑞西
Steve Geraci.
我把能想起来的全说了
I said all I remember about the girl.
别再问了
And don't ask again
我不会再问你
I ain't gonna ask you.
他会
He is.
真探
第一季第八集[季终]
苍蝇变多了
Them flies are gettin' thick.
应该给你好好冲一冲了
Somebody ought to give you a good hosin'.
靠温度是没用的
Heat ain't helpin'.
看来你还能再活一天
Eh, reckon you'll keep another day.
乖一点  我中午给你带点水来
Be good, I'll bring you some more water round noon.
再见  爸爸
Bye, Daddy.
拜托  别咬
Come on. Come on.
别咬
Come on.
我有今晚剧院的票
But I have tickets for the theater this evening,
是我一直想看的一场表演
to a show I was looking forward to, and I get, well,
我遇到些不太合理的事情
kind of unreasonable about things like that.
如此专业的表演
With such expert play-acting,
你使得这个演播厅如同剧院一般
you make this very room a theater...
你去散步了吗
You have a good walk?
去了  亲爱的
Yes, my dear.
今早最棒的散步
Top-notch walk this morning.
最棒的运动
Top-notch constitutional.
自从我留下印记已经都几个星期了
It's been weeks since I left my mark.
他们去看了吗
Would that they had eyes to see.
你能不要把比莉小姐带进来吗
Don't you get Miss Billie in here with them dirty feet!
不好意思啊  老伙计
Sorry, old chap.
你今天要做爱吗
You want to make flowers today?
贝蒂  我现在
Now, Betty,
有很重要的事要做
I have very important work to do.
我
My...
已接近飞升之境
ascension removes me from the disc and the loop.
我就要到最后阶段了
I'm near final stage.
有时候的早上
Some mornings,
我能看到飞往地狱的飞机
I can see the infernal plane.
你已经大约有三个星期没有跟我做爱了
You haven't made flowers on me for maybe 3 weeks.
让我非常难过
Makes me sad is all.
来我腿上坐着  小姑娘
Ah, come up in me lap, lass.
这里来  让我安慰你的痛苦
Here, and let me comfort ye in your distress.
你重新使我开心起来来
You're make fun of me again.
不  我为什么要这么做呢
No, why'd I do a thing like that, huh?
因为你特别机灵吗
Is it because you're ne so bright?
因为你的总是呆呆的吗
Because of your head bein' so slow and like?
快放我走  不然你会欲火焚身的
Oh, you better let me go 'cause I'm burn your eggs.
能跟我说说爷爷吗
Couldn't you tell me about Grampa?
我在甘蔗田里
I was in the cane fields,
趁我单独一人的时候他抓住了我
and he caught me when I was alone.
泥土很温暖
And the dirt was warm.
我感到暖暖的泥土触着我背
I felt the dirt warm on my back.
克里奥尔自然步道
还有160公里
要是我得说第二遍的话你的膝盖骨就不保了
You're gonna lose a kneecap if I got to ask you again.
把它从袋子里拿出来放进录像机里
Take it out of the bag and put it in the machine.
别看我
Don't look at me.
看屏幕
Look at the TV.
天呐
Oh, Jesus Christ.
你为什么给我看这个
Why are you showing me this?!
这小女孩就是你说的去看她爸爸的那个
That little girl is the one you said went to see her daddy.
玛丽·方特诺特  大约在1990年
Marie Fontenot, circa 1990.
我上交过一份失踪青少年报告
I took a m-missing juvenile report.
当我回过头去跟进的时候
And when I went back to follow up on it,
这份文件上写着"报告有误"
the file said, "report made in error."
我没这么写过
I never wrote that.
我带着它去找了治安官  泰德·柴尔德里斯
So I marched it right in to the sheriff, Ted Childress.
他已经去世了
He's dead now.
是他写的
He did it.
治安官怎么说
What'd the sheriff say?
他说是他改的
He said he'd changed it,
他认识这孩子的父母
that he knew the mother and the father,
叔叔和婶婶
the aunt and the uncle.
这事就是侄女从他这儿搬走了之类的
It was a niece once removed from him or somethin'.
这就是行政系统
It was the chain of command.
没法改变
No reason to change it.
我只是照上级的要求做
I just... follow what the big man says.
就是...
It's...
这么一回事
how this all works.
我试着去找孩子的母亲
I--I tried to get back with the mother.
我试着去找她
I tried to get back with her.
她不见了  她走了
She was gone! She split!
文件不见了
The file was gone!
却没人提起
Nobody said a word!
后来  我在泰德的推荐下
Later that year, I was in State CID,
当了州属刑事调查员
on Ted's recommendation!
我没有什么理由重新去查证
Nobody ever gave me a reason to second-guess it!
这就是行政系统
It's chain of command!
对吗
Right?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得他没说谎
I don't think he's lying...
就他所知的这些
as far as he knows.
就我所知的这些
As far as I know?
你他妈是怎么回事  伙计
What the fuck is with you, man?!
如果我们稍作安排
Might be a whole lot safer
可能会更安全  小马
if we staged something, Marty...
把玛莎拉蒂推到护栏外
sent the Maserati over the guardrail.
孩子们  慢点跑
Boys, slow down.
在外面小心点
Be careful out there.
你要是饿了  我从自助餐厅给你拿份午餐来
I can get you a cafeteria lunch if you're hungry.
没事的  小姐
That's all right, Miss.
我得继续工作
I've got to get on with my work.
今天事很多
Lots to do today.
好吧
Oh, all right.
我们把你的手机和枪拿走
We're gonna hang onto your phone and your gun
等确保没事了就立刻寄给你
till we get safe and mail them to you once we know we are.
有问题吗  史蒂夫
That work for you, Steve?
当然他娘的没问题
You can bet your ass it doesn't.
而且你要叫我杰瑞西治安官  白痴
And it's Sheriff Geraci to you, shitheel.
史蒂夫
Now, look, Steve,
你想摆平这些操蛋事
you're gonna want to swing some dick on this thing.
我告诉你几条不行的原因
I'm gonna give you a couple reasons why you won't.
首先  我们在你的地盘找到这盘录像带
First off, we found this tape in your possession.
上面有你曾说没失踪的那个小姑娘的视频
It's a video of the little girl that you said was not missing.
第二  所有的发现都在律师手里
Second off, all findings are with lawyers,
准备寄给媒体  联邦探员
ready to be forwarded to media outlets, feds,
刑事调查员和美国检察官
CID, U.S. Attorneys,
要么我们中的一位会拿到逮捕令
should either one of us get sworn a warrant
要么就彻底地人间蒸发
or if either one of us just fall off the face of the fuckin' earth,
像你那个地区的人所希望的那样
as people are want to do in your neck of the woods.
所以你还是想想那个小姑娘吧  史蒂夫
So you just think about that little girl, Steve.
那你的船呢
What about your boat?
那不是我的船
That ain't my boat.
-你知道是谁的吗  -我以前从来没见过
- You know whose boat that is? - I never seen it before.
你们会遭报应的  一群混蛋
It's gonna come back on you, you assholes,
一定会遭报应的
one way or another.
想想那个小女孩吧  史蒂夫
You just think about that little girl, Steve.
相当长一段时间我都会想你的  拉斯特
For quite some time, I'm gonna be thinking about you, Rust.
还有一件事  史蒂夫
Hey, one other thing, Steve.
我找了个狙击手老朋友
Got an old sniper pal, all right?
酬金已经付清了
Contract's already been paid.
你总有一天会落到我们手上的
Me or Marty,
等着你的不是手铐就是棺材
we see cuffs or coffins,
你将会死得毫无尊严
you're gonna end up in the dirt.
然后你的名声将会一塌胡涂
Then we're gonna smear your name.
我也给你准备了点东西  小子
I got something coming for you, baby.
你的恐吓对我完全没用
Your psycho bit don't cur me, boy!
你听到没有
You hear me?!
这他妈怎么回事
What the fuck?!
你说我这是空谈者还是行动派  史蒂夫
I strike you as more of a talker or a doer, Steve?
这他妈是我的车
That's my fuckin' car!
真他妈该死
God damn it!
为生活干杯  死胖子
L'chaim, fatass.
你这个婊子养的
You motherfuckers!
我操你妈
Fuck you!
亨利·塔特尔和吉尔·塔特尔
那个柴尔德里斯治安官
This old Sheriff Childress.
他没有小孩  也没有任何亲属信息
He's got no kids, no location on any of his relatives.
你觉得他们有没有可能把出生证明销掉了
You think they could have wiped out birth records?
我觉得有可能
I don't see why not.
沿海的医院有一半都不在了
I mean, half those hospitals along the coast are gone now.
我们在亲属这条线
You know, we got a dead end
貌似陷入死胡同了
on the relations and, uh,
你手上还有什么
what else is there?
案情档案
Case files.
你想看98年之前的还是之后的
You want pre-'98 or after?
之后的
After.
我们必须换个新角度看这些记录  小马
We're gonna have to be looking at these records with fresh eyes, Marty.
就像我们对此案毫不知情一样
All right? Like we're totally green.
为什么会是绿耳朵
Why green ears?
假设那是我们要找的人
I mean, assuming that's our guy.
我不知道  不确定
I don't know, exactly.
我猜可能
My thinking was it was probably
有点靠谱吧  你懂的
leaves of some kind, you know,
我们确实知道他穿过树林袭击了她
'cause we do know that he came at her through the woods.
怎么了  你在想什么
Why? What you thinking?
在找95年朵拉·兰在伊拉斯拉票的照片
Looking for '95 Dora Lange canvassing photos from Erath.
为什么
Why?
这个...
Well...
拉斯特
Rust.
过来
Come over here.
你觉得  当时  那个...
Now, you think, back then, does that--
那个你觉得...
does that look like a fresh...
像新刷的油漆吗
paint job to you?
-绿耳朵  -对
- The green ears. - Yeah.
也许是油漆沾到帽子上了
Maybe they were sticking out of his hat.
也许他是刷的那栋房子
Maybe he painted that house.
我去查查旧地址
I'm going to look up old addressees.
可以啊  兄弟
Fuck you, man.
有些事10年来一直困扰着我
Something's been bugging me the last 10 years.
不是每天  时不时的
Not every day, just now and then.
我们打了一架
We went at it,
你辞职那天
day you quit.
你让着我了吗
Were you holding back?
没有  我怎么可能让着你
No, I don't see how I could've.
你知道
Oh, yeah, you do.
你一直都有那种...
You--you've always had such
自己的膨胀意识
an inflated idea of yourself.
什么意思
Meaning what?
意思看起来很他妈自大
Meaning it seems pretty damn arrogant
跟我打架让着我也很可能
to hold back in a fight with me.
你觉得你能打倒我吗
You think you could have put me down?
我不知道
Ah, I don't know.
我可能会杀了你
Hell, I'd have had to kill you.
你当时太愤怒了
You were so goddamn mad.
是  没错
Yeah, um...ahem.
她告诉我时  她说
You know, when she told me, she said
不要怪你  那不是你愿意的
not to blame you, that it wasn't your choice.
你...喝多了  而且...
You, uh, were drunk and...
是她主动的
she made it happen.
每个人都有选择  小马
Everybody's got a choice, Marty.
操  我觉得得怪你
Shit, I sure blamed you.
怪我  为什么
Blamed me? For what?
因为你把一个好女人
For pushing a good woman
逼到利用我和我们的搭档关系
to the point where she had to use me,
才能摆脱你的程度
use our partnership to get rid of you.
因为你是个撒谎的混蛋
For just being a lying sack of shit.
如果不是你也有意  她也不会找上你
You know, she couldn't have used you, you didn't want some.
果然说到这了
There you go.
每个人都有选择
Everybody's got a choice.
而且  她依然关心你
And yet, she still cares about you.
你当时去找她了  我猜
You went to see her, I take it.
-而她来了酒吧  -什么
- She came out to the bar. - What?
-什么时候  -她来看看你
- When? - Yeah, she was just checking on you,
想要确保我没把你扯进任何麻烦里
wanted to make sure I wasn't getting you in any trouble.
你不应该告诉我
You should have fuckin' told me.
也许吧  我猜
Yeah, maybe. I guess.
我想最好连她的名字都不要提
I reckoned it was best to just avoid her name.
不想被审判  你从来不喜欢被人指手画脚
Didn't want to invite judgments. You never liked being judged.
是的  你说的对  不喜欢  特别是被你
No, you're right, I don't. Not by you.
我什么都没说
Well, I didn't say a word.
我从你脸上的表情就能看出来
Well, I could read it all over your face.
问题在于你的脸
Well, then the problem's with your face,
而不是我的
not mine.
你知道吗  对于你这样拒人于千里之外的人
It's hard to find something in a man
很难跟你有什么共同语言
who rejects people as much as you do, you know that?
我从来没教过你怎么生活  小马
I never told you how to live your life, Marty.
不不不  你只是居高临下批判别人
No, no, no, you just sat in judgment.
我们作为有知觉的肉体
Look, as sentient meat,
不管我们的身份多么虚幻
however illusory our identities are,
也是通过价值判断来塑造的
we craft those identities by making value judgments.
每个人都会评判别人  一直都这样
Everybody judges, all the time.
你要质疑这点  你就没活对
Now, you got a problem with that, you're living wrong.
什么叫"有知觉的肉体"
What's "Scented meat"?
有什么能帮忙的吗
Can I help you?
95年的时候你们住在这里吗
Did you happen to live here back in '95?
不  那会儿我们不住这里
No, we didn't live here back then.
这是我奶奶家
This is my grandma's place.
你奶奶  她在我们这儿吗
Grandma, she still with us?
-你是问她还活着吗  -是的
- Alive, you mean? - Yeah.
活着呢  住在阿比维尔的
Yeah, she's in an old folks' place.
养老院
Abbeville.
希尔夫人
Mrs. Hill, now,
接下来的问题可能有点匪夷所思
this is a very strange question,
但你还记得94或95年冬天的事吗
but, um, do you remember back in the winter of '94 or '95,
你的房子重新刷漆了吗
did you get your house painted?
刷了  没错  我刷了
I did. Yes, I did.
很漂亮的绿色漆
A nice green.
但我记不起那颜色叫什么了
Don't remember what they call it anymore.
你还记不记得
Do you happen to remember
谁给你刷的房子
who it was that painted your house?
记得
Well, yes.
名字记不清了  但他们是一帮好人
I don't remember the name, but they were nice men.
他们在我们的教区工作
They worked for our parish.
打理院子  粉刷房子
Yard work, house-painting.
他们对我们教堂有折扣
My church, they got a discount.
以那个价格说  他们活儿干的很漂
Good work for fair pay back then. Mmm.
那你还记不记得
Do you remember, by any chance,
他们的名字或是其他细节
names or just any other details?
我记得  粉刷整栋房子的外墙
I remember they charged $250
他们收了我250美元
for the whole house exterior.
其中有一个人
And one of the men--
一个年轻人
the younger one--he had
下巴那里有一个很大的疤
scarring all along the bottom of his face.
莉莉女士  当时你或者你丈夫有工作吗
Miss Lilly, back then, did you or your husband work?
我丈夫布奇是个工作狂
My husband, Butch, he's always worked.
他要出海去做市政服务
He was offshore for City Services.
他交税吗
Did he pay his taxes?
从来不落  那让他受益不少
Always. Heh! A lot of good it did him.
十分感谢
Thank you so much.
-您帮了我们大忙  -谢谢
- You've been really helpful. - Thank you.
找到了
There you go.
美国个人所得税申报单
94年12月  她丈夫注销了
Husband took the write-off. December '94.
备案
公司与企业
布奇·希尔付给
$265 paid by Butch Hill
柴尔德里斯家族维修公司的265美元
to Childress and Son Maintenance.
公共记录 商业与贸易
有了
Yes, yes. Here we go.
公共记录 商业与贸易
1978年营业执照最初发给
Business license first issued
比利·柴尔德里斯
to Billy Childress, 1978.
这个名字就是
Same name as that--
-那个治安官  -没错
- Sheriff. - Yeah.
好
Uh...OK.
直到2004年营业执照都没有更新
Business license not renewed since 2004.
好了
Ok.
这名字在公共记录中出现很多次
Name comes up a lot in public records.
看来他们有很多教区合同
Looks like they had a lot of parish contracts.
公共场所  国有财产  庭院设计  没错
Public, state property, landscape, yeah.
我就想要这个  我要知道他那时在哪儿
That's what I want. I want to know where he was.
好的
Ok.
整个沿海地区都有
All over the coast, OK?
看起来他们给很多学校
It looks like they did maintenance
做过维修
for a lot of schools,
还有操场和墓地
playgrounds, cemeteries--
查查比利·柴尔德里斯的背景  找到他儿子
Run a background on Billy Childress. Find his son.
好
Ok.
找到了
Here we go.
威廉·李·柴尔德里斯
William Lee Childress,
母亲莉兹白·柴尔德里斯
born to Lizbeth Childress,
生于1944年  伊拉斯
1944, Erath.
没有子女记录
No son showing.
车辆管理记录  驾照过期
Address--DMV, old license--
检查地点27号高速公路南段
highway 27 South.
滚出去  快
Get out of here! Go on!
你能闻到性爱的味道吗  比莉小姐
Can you smell the flowers, Miss Billie?
一份给政府  一份给刑事调查局
One to the feds, one to State CID,
一份给州检  一份给联邦检查院
one to State Attorney, one to U.S. Attorney.
两份给全国报社
Two to national papers,
两份给地方报社  两份给国家电视台
two to local papers, two to national channels.
我们找到的证据
It's the whole story,
基本都在这里了
near as we got it.
每个里面都有一盘磁带的副本
There's a copy of the tape in each one,
案件卷宗  我们录的证言
the case files, our depositions--
我们了解的一切
everything we got.
如果过了24小时我没来让你停手
Now, 24 hours passes and I don't stop you,
就把他们全发出去
mail 'em all out.
然后藏起来一段时间
Then lay low a while.
那个案子怎么样了  查尔斯湖的那个
So how's that case going, uh, Lake Charles?
跟你没关系
None of your fucking business.
你的老搭档告诉过你什么吗
Your old partner give you anything yet?
和你毫无关系
None of your fucking business.
你为什么给我打电话
Why'd you call me?
为什么不打给我搭档
Why not my partner?
你  我能理解  他  我不能
You, I can read. Him, I can't.
你为什么要理解我们
And why would you need to do that?
你们两个之前在做什么
What have you two been doing?
熬那么多夜
All those late nights.
就上个月在你办公室里
Your offices the last month.
上帝啊  就那些吗
Christ, and that's it?
你就知道那些吗
That's all you got?
虽然不该让你知道
Ain't for you to know,
但我知道你在调查
but I know you been pulling case files
整个南路易斯安那州的案件
all over south Louisiana.
跟科尔以前的想法有关吗
It's about Cohle's theory, way back?
他和你合作
He's fucking with you.
他是个操纵者  一个反社会的人
He's a manipulator, sociopath.
你知道的
You know this.
你了解山姆·塔特尔家族
Do you know about Sam Tuttle,
的所有分支吗
all the branches of the family?
比如  沼泽文化
The, uh, marsh cult,
恶魔崇拜  儿童献祭什么的
devil worship, child sacrifices?
你听起来很像科尔
You sound like Cohle.
线索似乎指向除了他以外的所有方向是吗
It points in every direction but him, huh?
我就知道你要那么说
Man, I knew you were gonna say that.
你知道一些事  但不想告诉我
You know something, you're obstructing.
我们不确定
We don't know,
但我们有一个想法
but we're following up an idea.
也许是错的  但是
May be nothing, but--
一段时间之后  我们发现了些事情
ahem--time comes, we--we know we got something,
如果你拿到线索  会做正确的事吗
you get a call, you gonna do the right thing?
你说了一个谜语  白人
You speak in Riddles to me, white man.
你的话又像科尔了
You sound like Cohle, again.
我们发现了一些事  你想要线索
We get something, do you want the call
还是想让线索落进别人手里
or you want it to go to someone else?
给我吧
Give it to me.
快点回来
Just make sure you come runnin'.
那个味道
That taste.
什么
What?
铝  铝灰
Aluminum, ash.
我以前尝过
I've tasted it before.
你还有幻觉吗
You still see things, ever?
从没真正消失过
It never stops, not really.
我脑袋受的刺激  是不会好起来的
What happened to my head, it's not something that gets better.
快到了
Uh, this is it.
给帕帕尼亚打电话
Call Papania.
该死  没信号
Shit. Can't get a signal.
我去借座机
I'm gonna ask to use the phone.
这样吧  还是我去吧
You know what? I'll go ask.
小马
Marty.
这就是我们要找的地方
This is the place.
你好
Hello.
见鬼
Aw, damn it!
不好意思  太太
Oh, pardon me, ma'am.
我们是专业测量员
Uh, we're professional surveyors
可是像初学者似的  在小路上迷失方向了
and got lost on these back roads like a couple of greenhorns.
而且手机没信号
Uh, cell phone is getting no service.
我能不能
Is there any way that I could, uh,
借用你的座机
use your phone?
我们没有座机  先生
We don't have no phone, Mister.
-那可太郁闷了  -是啊
- That's too bad. - Yeah.
别叫了
No, I said!
别吵了  否则我踢你了
Stop it over there or I kick you!
能否麻烦你给我一杯水
Could I trouble you for a glass of water?
这附近的水不是很好
The water around here is not real good.
坐下  别叫了  否则我踢你了
Sit, I said! Stop it! I'm gonna kick you!
比利·查尔德里斯在哪
Where's Billy Childress?
-老比利吗  -是的
- Old Bill? - Yeah.
他就在这房子里  先生
He's in this house, Mister.
这不是他的房子吧
Oh, th-this isn't his?
有人跟你一起住吗
Well, who--who do you, uh, who do you live here with?
我觉得你该走了
I think you should go now.
他在什么地方
Mm-hmm, uh, hey, where is he?
萦绕在我们周围
All around us,
从你出生之前
before you were born...
在你死后
and after you die.
不  住手
No! No!
滚出我家  先生
Get out of my house, mister!
小马  去屋里检查下
Marty, clear the house!
不许动
Don't move!
跪下  快点
On your knees, now!
快跪下
On your knees! Now!
不要
No.
妈的
Fuck.
是人都有电话
Everybody has a phone.
你的在哪
Where's yours?
他不会饶了你的
He's gonna come for you.
他比任何人都邪恶
He's worse than anybody.
不要  你
No, you--
-你他妈的电话在哪  -不要
- Where's your fuckin' phone?! - No!
跟我来  小家伙
Come with me, little man.
快跟我进来
Come in here with me.
拉斯特
Rust?
在
Yeah!
-拉斯特  -在这
- Rust! - Here!
进来吧  小牧师
Come on inside, little priest.
往右边  小牧师
To your right, little priest.
踏上新娘之路
Take the bride's path.
这里即是卡寇莎
This is Carcosa.
你知道他们对我做过什么吗
You know what they did to me?
我要将这些
What I will do to
偿还给所有的人类子孙
all the sons and daughters of man.
那个受神庇佑的雷金
You blessed Reggie...
德沃尔
Dewall.
都是我的信徒
Acolytes.
是我旅途的见证者
Witnesses to my journey.
以及我的爱人
Lovers.
我无愧于心
I am not ashamed.
来与我一起赴死  小牧师
Come die with me, little priest.
拉斯特
Rust?
Rust!
现在  摘掉你的面具
Now, take off your mask.
拉斯特
Rust.
操
Oh, fuck.
他下手很重  小马
Ah, he cut me pretty good, Marty.
不  拉斯特
No, Rust.
不太糟
It ain't bad.
-第一组进屋  -是  长官
- Get me a forward team in the house. - Yes, sir.
-第二组抄到后面那房子  -往后包抄
- Get me a second team on that back house. - Going around back.
警官  照亮那片树林
Deputy, light up those woods.
这里
Here!
这里  我们在这里
Here! We're here!
这是我记得的最后一件事
That's the last thing I remember.
我躺在地上
I was on the ground.
听着警笛声
Sirens.
叫着我朋友的名字
Saying my friend's name.
那女的是个疯子
The girl's a nut.
她说了点东西  但是...
She talked some, but...
都是关于那群人  萨尔弗的恋童癖
This group of guys, pedophiles in Sulphur.
对伏都教的崇拜
Voodoo worship.
科尔射死的是那老人的儿子
Man Cohle shot dead was the old man's son.
没犯罪记录
No records.
女的至少是他同父异母的妹妹
Girl was at least a half-sister.
-根据DNA比对  -够了
- DNA comparison-- - Stop.
够了  我不想再听
Really, man. Stop. I don't want to hear it.
我们还在进行分类登记
Well, we're still cataloguing everything,
但在小木屋里  我们找到了凶器
but knife casts came back from that shed.
一把跟查尔斯湖那个案子吻合
One of them matched our Lake Charles case,
另一把跟朵拉·兰的伤口吻合
another matched Dora Lange's wounds.
上面有他的指纹
Had his prints.
这次抓捕行动  我们欠你的
Look, man, we owe you on this collar.
拉斯特怎么样了
How's Rust?
还没醒
Hasn't woke up.
手术后就一直昏迷着
Been in a coma since surgery.
你一到这  她们就来了
They came by, you first got here.
-谢谢你  泰德  -不客气
- Thank you, Ted. - No.
夫人
Ma'am.
见到你们真好
It's so good to see y'all.
我没想到你们会来
I...I didn't expect you.
你还好吗
How are you?
挺好的
Oh, good.
我没事
I'm fine.
我会没事的
Yeah, I--I'll be fine.
我真的
I mean...I--I am...
没事
fine.
接下来播出的是关于
And now the latest news update
被怀疑是路易斯安那连环杀人犯的
in the case of alleged Louisiana serial murderer
埃罗尔·威廉·柴尔德里斯的最新消息
Errol William Childress.
这起事件两周前在全国范围内传播开来
It's a story that first broke nationwide two weeks ago,
当时有两位现职为私家侦探的
when two former police officers,
前警官向各大报社和执法机构
now private detectives, released information
放出了这个消息
to a number of news and law enforcement agencies.
最新消息证实已在嫌犯家中
Our last update confirmed physical evidence
找到其与大量失踪人口
at the suspect's home proved connections
有关的物证
to dozens of missing persons.
同时  州总检察长与联调局
In the meantime, the State Attorney General and the FBI
已经否认了被告与路易斯安那州参议员
have discredited rumors that the accused was in some way
埃德温·塔特尔家族有关的传言
related to the family of Louisiana Senator Edwin Tuttle.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
没什么  护士说我可以进来
Nothin'. Nurse said I could come in.
你是在看我睡觉吗
Are you watching me sleep?
我才刚进来
Well, you know what? I just got here.
正打算走  结果你就醒了
I was gonna leave, but then you woke up.
天哪  你到底什么毛病
Jesus, what's your fuckin' problem?
没毛病  你有什么毛病
Nothing. What's your problem?
我无牵无挂
Not a care in the world.
我看见他了  小马
I saw him, Marty.
他95年时在佩利肯岛的校园
He was mowing that schoolyard
修剪草坪
on Pelican Island in '95.
我看不出他有多高
I couldn't tell how tall he was
因为他当时坐在那儿  而且他的脸
'cause he was sittin' and his face was--
很脏  但我看见他了
it was dirty, but I...I saw him.
就是这事困扰着你
That's what's bugging you?
塔特尔  还有视频里那些人
Tuttles, fucking men in the video.
还有漏网之鱼
We didn't get 'em all.
那也在所难免
Yeah, and we ain't gonna get 'em all.
世界就是这样  至少我们抓到了我们的犯人
That ain't what kind of world it is, but we got ours.
我不该躺在这的
I'm not supposed to be here.
我明天再来看你  兄弟
I'll come back by tomorrow, buddy.
为什么
Why?
死性不改
Don't ever change, man.
医生说
Doc said, uh,
可能还得再待两天
probably get out in a few days.
我会帮你弄辆车  找个住的地方
I'll make sure you got a ride, place to stay.
我自己会搞定的
Yeah, I'll figure it out.
已经搞定了
Well, it's already been figured out.
对了
Oh, hey.
给你带了件礼物
I brought you something.
我们这是要订婚了吗
Are we getting engaged?
那要是求婚戒指  我会包装得更好点的
If we were getting engaged, I'd have got a nicer ribbon.
你居然还记得
You remembered.
是啊
Yeah.
别在这待着了
Ah, let's get out from under this roof, huh?
同意
Good idea.
我自己可以推轮椅的
Hey, I can push two goddamn wheels on my own.
没错  我应该让你自己来
Yeah, I ought to let you
然后再把缝线扯开  闭嘴吧
and rip out your fuckin' stitches. Stop it.
感觉好点了吗  头上的伤
Feeling better? Your head, I mean.
我不想再呆在这了  小马
I shouldn't even fuckin' be here, Marty.
我觉得没人
I believe "No shit" is the proper response
是乐意住院的
to that observation.
我不是说住院
Nah, I don't mean like that.
是别的事
It's something else.
那跟我说说呗  拉斯特
Well, so... talk to me, Rust.
有那么一刻
There was a moment --
当我陷在黑暗之中时
I know when I was under in the dark
有什么东西
that something...
不管我是深陷于什么之中
whatever I'd been reduced to,
甚至没有知觉
you know, not even consciousness.
那是一种在黑暗里的模糊意识
It was a vague awareness in the dark,
我可以
and I could--
我可以感觉到我整个人
I could feel my definitions
正在消逝
fading.
而在那黑暗之下  还有另外一种感觉
And beneath that... darkness, there was another kind.
更深层次的
It was--it was deeper,
很温暖  就像是真的一样
warm, you know, like a substance.
我可以感觉到
I could feel, man,
我知道  我知道我的女儿
and I knew, I knew my daughter
在那里等着我
waited for me there.
清楚万分
So clear.
我可以感觉得到她
I could feel her.
我可以感觉到
I could feel...
我还可以感觉到一点我爸爸的存在
I could feel a piece of my--my pop, too.
就像是我在所有我
It was like I was a part of everything
深爱过的人之中  我们全都在
that I ever loved, and we were all...
我们三个人  都在慢慢消逝
the 3 of us, just-- just fadin' out.
而我只要放手就行了
And all I had to do was let go...
我也确实这么做了
and I did.
我说"黑暗"
I said, "Darkness, yeah, yeah."
然后我就消失了
And I disappeared.
但是我仍然可以  可以感觉到
But I could-- I could still feel
她对我的爱意
her love there,
浓于以前
even more than before.
只有
Nothing...
只有爱意紧紧包围着我
There was nothing but that love.
接着我醒了
Then I woke up.
你不是有一次吃晚饭的时候告诉过我
Didn't you tell me one time at dinner
有这么一次
once, maybe, about you used to...
你以前会编点星空的故事
you used to make up stories about the stars?
是的  那是
Yeah, that was--
那是
that was, um,
我在阿拉斯加州的时候
in A-Alaska,
在浩瀚夜空之下
under the--under the night skies.
你躺在那儿  往天上看
Yeah, you used to lay there and look up,
遥望星空
yeah, at the stars?
没错  你还记得我
Yeah, and you remember I...
我17岁之前都没看过电视
I never watched a TV till I was 17,
所以平时没什么可做的
so there wasn't much to fuckin' do out there
只能到处走走看看  以及
besides walk around and explore and--
以及
And...
以及仰望星空  编点故事
and look up at the stars and make up stories.
比如呢
Like what?
跟你说吧  小马  我每天晚上
I tell you, Marty, I've been up in that room
都在房间里看着窗外  想着
looking out those windows every night here and just thinking...
这不过就是个故事
It's just one story.
最老的故事
The oldest.
是什么
What's that?
光明与黑暗之战
Light versus dark.
我知道我们不在阿拉斯加  但是
I know we ain't in Alaska, but...
看起来黑暗占了上风
appears to me that the dark has a lot more territory.
是啊
Yeah.
你说得对
You're right about that.
听着
Hey, listen, hey.
怎么
Yeah, what?
带我去车上吧
Why don't you point me in the direction of the car, man?
我这辈子在医院里待得够久的了
I've spent enough of my fuckin' life in hospitals.
上帝啊
Jesus. Oh. You know what?
我虽然不赞成
I'd protest,
但是看起来你还死不了
but it occurs to me that you're unkillable.
你要回去穿点衣服吗
You want to go back, get clothes or anything?
不用了  留在那儿的东西都不要了
No, anything I left back there, I don't need.
你知道  关于天空  你弄错了
You know, you're looking at it wrong, the...sky thing.
为什么
How is that?
以前  这个世界只有黑暗
Well, once, there was only dark.
要我说  是光明占了上风
If you ask me, the light's winning.